The Happiest, Dopiest, Grumpiest, Sneeziest movie of the year.
Snow White and the Seven Dwarfs is a fantasy,
animation, family film directed by David Hand.
A beautiful girl, Snow White, takes refuge in the forest in the house of
seven dwarfs to hide from her stepmother, the wicked Queen.
The Queen is jealous because she wants to be known as "the fairest in
the land," and Snow White's beauty surpasses her own.
Snow White (voice) (uncredited), played by Adriana Caselotti.
Queen / Witch (voice) (uncredited), played by Lucille La Verne.
Prince (voice) (uncredited), played by Harry Stockwell.
Doc (voice) (uncredited), played by Roy Atwell.
Sleepy / Grumpy / Dopey (hiccups) (voice) (uncredited), played by Pinto Colvig.
Happy (voice) (uncredited), played by Otis Harlan.
Snow White and the Seven Dwarfs is a 1937 American animated musical fantasy film produced by Walt Disney and
released by RKO Radio Pictures, based on the 1812 German fairy tale "Snow White" by the Brothers Grimm.
The film was supervised by David Hand and a team of five sequence directors: Perce
Pearce, William Cottrell, Larry Morey, Wilfred Jackson, and Ben Sharpsteen.
It is the first animated feature film produced in the United
States and the first cel animated feature film.
Snow White premiered at the Carthay Circle Theatre in Los Angeles, California, on December 21,
1937, and went into general release in the United States on February 4, 1938.
Despite initial doubts from the film industry, it was a critical and commercial success, with international earnings of more than $8 million during its initial release
against a $1.5 million production cost, becoming the highest-grossing film of 1938, and briefly holding the record of the highest-grossing sound film of all time.
It was also the highest-grossing animated film for 55 years.
The popularity of the film has led to its being re-released theatrically
many times, until its home video release in the 1990s.
Adjusted for inflation, it is one of the top-ten performers at the North American box office and is
still the highest-grossing animated film with an adjusted gross of $2,297,000,000.
Worldwide, its inflation-adjusted earnings top the animation list.
Snow White was nominated for Best Musical Score at the Academy Awards in 1938, and the
next year, producer Walt Disney was awarded an honorary Oscar for the film.
This award was unique, consisting of one normal-sized,
plus seven miniature Oscar statuettes.
They were presented to Disney by Shirley Temple.
Snow White was a landmark release in the early animation industry, and it is widely regarded as one of the
greatest and most influential films ever made, credited with ushering in the golden age of animation.
Disney's take on the fairy tale has had a significant cultural impact, resulting in popular theme
park attractions, a video game, a Broadway musical, and a 2025 live-action film remake.
In 1989, the United States Library of Congress deemed the film "culturally, historically, or aesthetically
significant" and selected it as one of the first 25 films for preservation in the National Film Registry.
The American Film Institute ranked it among the 100 greatest American films, and also
named the film as the greatest American animated film of all time in 2008.
The film explores themes of witch, dying and death,
princess, becoming an adult, dwarf.
The tone is lighthearted.